Chris: I think this guy was riding by the seat of his pants here, but he sprung the trap at
Chris: what looks like either $7.5 or $15 million are all considered a good day for him.
Tyler: Nice work there, Chris.
Tyler: You're a pseudonymous version of Chris that actually executed this attack.
Tyler: You won't admit to it, but can't get along with him, but you could delegate work to
Chris: him.
Chris: Are you asking if I have developed a Jackson-style parasocial relationship with Claude?
Chris: Is that the question?
Tyler: Not imply quite Jackson level because I think that's like extreme.
Tyler: Like I think that there's a little bit of like almost like quasi-romantic, but like
Jackson: on an emotional level, not on a physical level.
Jackson: Yeah.
Tyler: Oh, we're about to break 10.
Jackson: Jeez, it just popped from six.
Jackson: It was six, like two minutes ago.
Chris: This time, you need to, you need to do the next one.
Insert: I think Jared just got wrecked on chain again and then we're getting a dividend from GTO.
Insert: All right, we're lives.
Jackson: What's up, everybody?
Jackson: It's Jackson Cook and we've got our boys.
Tyler: What up, it's Tyler.
Chris: And also Chris.
Jackson: And Chris still probably has thumb issues.
Jackson: Chris, how, how is the thumb going?
Chris: So brace off today.
Chris: I can't tell if it's getting better or worse, but you know, I've just decided, you know,
Chris: as we talked about last podcast, so this is something I'm going to have to live with because
Chris: it's either this crippling thumb issue or the keyboard, and I've made my decision.
Jackson: So you've just, just disregarded Dr. Tyler's recommendation.
Chris: Yeah, I think I'm just going to truck through it.
Chris: I think it's, I think it's getting better, but it's been this way for a while, so it
Chris: could be illusory.
Jackson: And Tyler, are you a doctor?
Tyler: Because on, you know, which jurisdiction we're talking about, but in this jurisdiction now,
Tyler: in the jurisdiction of the podcast, maybe.
Jackson: Oh yeah, but maybe the pain doctor is of all the burns you dish out.
Jackson: Okay.
Jackson: And, uh, I don't know.
Jackson: Let's get straight into it.
Jackson: We're going to drop into purple fortune, Chris.
Jackson: It's purple fortune going.
Chris: Okay.
Tyler: Yeah.
Tyler: We're trying something a little bit new this time where in the past with purple fortune,
Tyler: we had Claude go off and like do some market research and come up with a trade idea and
Tyler: then tell us why.
Tyler: But I thought it would be like a little bit more fun to have Claude read our outline and
Tyler: our topics for the episode and then choose a thematic perp to invest in.
Tyler: So it's, you know, tied in with the episode.
Tyler: And so based on this one, Claude chose that we should long Gito and the thesis here is
Tyler: hold the sandwich.
Tyler: All right.
Tyler: So, uh, Gito is a token on Solana, uh, basically, okay.
Tyler: This week the market learned MEV is in a crime.
Tyler: It's a cashflow.
Tyler: Gito runs 95% of Solana staking, takes the majority of priority fee volume and just shipped
Tyler: a terminal that routes the skim back to token holders.
Tyler: Meanwhile, the most feared independent sandwich operator on a theorem just got liquidated
Tyler: by his own approvals in our tistle.
Tyler: The artisanal era of MEV is dying and the incorporated era is consolidating.
Tyler: You are not betting on extraction.
Tyler: You were betting that extraction pays a dividend and monopolies at the toll booth get rerated.
Tyler: All right.
Tyler: That sounds like a solid thesis to me, will it play out over the course of an hour?
Tyler: I'm not really here.
Chris: I mean, it's doing great.
Chris: Like I don't, I don't know if this has anything to do with the timing and, uh, you know, goodness
Chris: of the research, but, uh, this might be our best one.
Chris: Like it, it's not close.
Tyler: We just have to write it all episode.
Tyler: I mean, the first episode we were up like 20 or $30 on our, um, oh, yeah, that was the,
Tyler: yeah.
Tyler: The, um, the semiconductor trade or the high performance memory.
Chris: Yeah.
Jackson: D ram.
Jackson: Before we were one liquidated it, oh man, we only went five X though.
Tyler: We could, we could be up a whole $6 if we had gone, you know, five X, we could be a
Chris: week on 25 X, I know, I know.
Chris: And the reason for that is because of fables guardrails.
Chris: I'm just, I just tell you now, I'll tell you now, Fable was like, bro, I won't let you
Tyler: gamble with more than five X leverage.
Chris: Yeah.
Chris: So I accidentally started it in not dangerously skip permissions mode.
Chris: I started it in auto mode and the guardrails were just like, it wouldn't let me place the
Chris: trade.
Chris: It wouldn't let me do it at 10 X.
Chris: So I was like, you know, whilst we're talking about on-chain fund movements, I was furiously,
Chris: uh, trying to work out what was, what was wrong with him.
Tyler: It turns out, yeah, wrong mode, but so if we used Kimmy K three for this Kimmy K three
Tyler: would be like, have you tried a hundred X and can I please set this up for you, sir?
Chris: I feel like Kimmy K three like would like leverage.
Chris: It's just like, I get a feeling, you know, um, at least three X, you know?
Tyler: Um, yeah, I feel like I learned so much about sandwich attacks from, uh, our AI selves.
Chris: Me too.
Chris: And like surprisingly little, uh, personal information was revealed by our AI counterparts,
Chris: which I appreciated deeply.
Tyler: Uh, yeah, we're still calibrating that, you know, our, uh, the AI has developed a world
Tyler: model of us and it has extracted our souls into the soul.md with such precision that
Tyler: when I first generated the transcript, it leaked some, you know, personal information
Tyler: from one of the hosts and put it into the public domain.
Tyler: So we had to go back to the drawing board a little bit, had something to do with pastrami.
Jackson: We were able to keep the metaphor in, but we had to take the rest out.
Tyler: Yeah.
Tyler: We had a very uncomfortable history of pastrami for someone in this podcast, so it was a little
Jackson: bit of a trigger warning.
Jackson: Um, yeah, I mean, speaking of more on the video, I had my girlfriend listen to the AI
Jackson: voice and she says, it doesn't sound like me.
Jackson: Have you guys had anybody listen to your AI voice and like heard what they have to say?
Chris: I mean, my mind doesn't sound like me at all.
Chris: But Tyler sounds exactly like him.
Chris: Like I can hear his headset in the AI recording.
Tyler: I noticed that as well.
Tyler: I didn't think it retrained either.
Tyler: Like I didn't tell it to get the audio from the last episode and to retrain the voices.
Tyler: So I thought I was going to be the same voices from the Presidio audio, but it does like
Tyler: bake in my headset vibe into it.
Jackson: That's awesome.
Jackson: And then back to, you know, Mev and sandwich attacks, you know, was the AI was the AI accurate
Jackson: and do we have more to add on it?
Chris: Yeah.
Chris: I was quite bang on.
Chris: Uh, it even, it revealed even extra details that I don't know where it got them.
Tyler: Well, I've been your soul that you have so much knowledge about MEV that is deep in your
Tyler: amygdala that fable somehow extracted.
Chris: Yeah.
Chris: I mean, it's weights and my weights were like, you know, overlapping just for this one thing,
Chris: maybe.
Chris: Um, yeah.
Chris: So I mean this particular exploit I think was notable for two reasons.
Chris: One, this is not the first time a Mev bot has been exploited.
Chris: There's a famous case of the low carb crusader, which Jared in particular managed to dodge
Chris: that one.
Chris: Uh, but secondly, this one was like extremely sophisticated.
Tyler: So are all the Mev bots named after food?
Tyler: Well, I guess that was a thing like food tokens were a thing as well.
Tyler: I'm just getting hungry.
Tyler: It's like naming all of these crypto things known for all of rhyming about food out of
Jackson: nowhere.
Chris: There, there may be some like strange on chain pathology there now that I think about it.
Chris: I think it originally was sandwiches, right?
Chris: And then like, I don't know, uh, it's going on and on.
Chris: Uh, but, but in this particular one, so what the person did, the attacker is, so there's
Chris: this concept of wrapping tokens and they created basically a fake wrapped token that looked
Chris: comparable to a real one exposed to the ability to wrap, uh, into that token, uh, and created
Chris: like a compelling looking arbitrage option using that fake wrapped token.
Chris: So they seeded an arbitrage opportunity with this fake wrapped token.
Chris: Uh, so the Jared bot with, with its limited control, saw this wrapped token and this arbitrage
Chris: and was like, okay, under this heuristic, I'm just going to wrap into this, you know,
Chris: fake version of wrapped teeth and then pocket this arbitrage, which was like maybe wrapped
Chris: teeth and real USDC.
Chris: Right.
Chris: Um, so at the start, this fake wrapper was working as intended.
Chris: So the bot would wrap the eth it would go and pocket this arbitrage opportunity, take
Chris: a couple of bits, um, but in the code at a certain block height, I believe the wrapper
Chris: cut over to no longer pulling the funds.
Chris: It would just keep giving back these fake wrapped tokens and never pulling the funds
Chris: out of Jared's wallet, which you're thinking like, okay, that's free money.
Chris: No.
Chris: Uh, so it would accrue all of these approvals.
Chris: And then after, you know, the person who made this fake wrapper was satisfied with the hall,
Chris: they pulled all of the eth out of Jared's wallet with these standing approvals at one
Chris: time.
Chris: Uh, so the, the reason this works is because
Tyler: That's how you do an exit scam though.
Tyler: Right.
Tyler: Is like you, you set the trap and then you wait until the, you know, the purse accumulates
Tyler: and accumulates and accumulates.
Tyler: And then you're like, okay, now's the time to rip the cord and you know, make my move
Chris: a hundred percent.
Tyler: And the reason too greedy and wait too long, but you also don't want to be too, uh, you
Tyler: know, if you give up too soon and reveal yourself and you leave money on the table, so to say
Chris: a hundred percent.
Chris: And I think this guy was riding by the seat of his pants here.
Chris: Um, but, uh, I like, he sprung the trap at what looks like either 7.5 or $15 million
Chris: or all considered, uh, a good day for him.
Tyler: Nice work there.
Tyler: Chris, I, you're, you're, uh, you know, pseudonymous version of Chris that actually executed
Tyler: this attack.
Tyler: He won't admit to it, but no, I have no, no knowledge that Chris black hats as a, uh,
Tyler: I don't even know if this is black hat.
Tyler: This is like kind of Robin hood E high feel to steal from a med bot is very like Robin
Tyler: hood.
Chris: I bet.
Chris: I mean, they're not like well loved on chain, I will say.
Chris: So I think this was, yeah, yeah.
Chris: Um, so I think the, the community is very split over whether this was a good or a bad
Chris: thing.
Tyler: All right.
Jackson: And for the arbitrages in the sandwich, is it always within like that stack of transactions
Jackson: or does it go across like multiple stacks of transactions to accomplish the arbitrage?
Chris: Uh, so in this case it was, uh, routing transactions across a couple of these fake pools.
Chris: So it was like a, I think a two or a three hop fake arbitrage.
Chris: Um, but like mev in general is not, you know, specific to single transaction, like often
Chris: transactions are bundled together into one to like achieve the desired outcome.
Tyler: Man, Chris, are you a, uh, code is law guy or a laws law guy?
Tyler: Am I like, I feel like when people see stuff like this, you know, I feel like the old,
Tyler: the old guard would be like code is law, so whatever you can accomplish on the blockchain,
Tyler: if you were able to accomplish, then like, you know, you're not like stealing from somebody,
Tyler: you're just, you put, you both put your money into this machine that had rules and you like
Tyler: discovered the rules better than they did.
Tyler: And therefore there's like no actual wrongdoing here.
Tyler: But then there's, you know, situations where almost all situations where the, you know,
Tyler: the law and the physical world, if it's a big enough, um, you know, hall or something
Tyler: that was perceived to have harmed people, they will intervene and charge people under,
Tyler: you know, the laws of that land.
Tyler: And that's a very different way to operate than the blockchain.
Tyler: Um, and I feel like there's some, like a good example of this was the guy who attacked mango
Tyler: markets.
Tyler: Do you remember that one?
Tyler: That one was like insane and very memorable to my mind, but it was kind of a similar thing
Tyler: where this guy like figured out how to exploit this defy protocol and he extracted a bunch
Tyler: of money and tokens.
Tyler: And then he kind of like screwed with them on chain and left some like messages taunting
Tyler: them.
Tyler: And then eventually he got doxxed and now he's like in jail because they doxxed him and then
Tyler: he got charged with like stealing money out of this defy protocol.
Tyler: But at the end of the day, like the defy protocol had its rules and he like, you know, might
Tyler: have exploited the rules in a way that they didn't want, but they made the rules.
Tyler: He exploited them.
Tyler: He got the money.
Tyler: Uh, but then like the United States, Southern district in New York was like, no dog, you're,
Tyler: you're Solana rules are meaningless are, are us government, you know, guns and Fiat taxes
Jackson: rules are, are, are what matter here.
Tyler: I think my morality is more sympathetic to the code is law side of that.
Tyler: But then the pragmatic thing is don't do things that are going to get you thrown in jail and
Tyler: the real world.
Chris: I completely agree with you.
Chris: I think it's case by case.
Chris: I think like in general, like ignoring the negative externalities of me giving this answer,
Chris: I would say I am a code is law guy, um, most of the time.
Chris: Uh, but you know, I think there are cases where like, you know, something has genuinely
Chris: been exploited in a way where maybe it is beneficial to, you know, prosecute like the
Chris: law is still the law, like the code is law, but the law is also the law.
Chris: Right?
Chris: So I think like, yeah, it's, it's, it's very case by case.
Tyler: Yeah.
Tyler: If the law is also the law though, then the blockchain is meaningless kind of way, because
Tyler: like, if, if the law can come in and supersede the actions that happened on the blockchain,
Tyler: and what's the point of the blockchain, it's, it's just like an open database that is controlled
Tyler: by the government.
Chris: Um, like, yeah, I think, I think for me, the, the, the chain is like, uh, a parallel thread.
Chris: Right?
Chris: Like, I don't think we're ever going to get to a place where, um, I mean, maybe we will
Chris: get to a place where everything is perfectly regulated, uh, which might fit into our next
Chris: topic, but, um, yeah, I think like it's just going to be a very messy interplay, uh, especially
Chris: as things heat up between like code law, uh, and, uh, law, law, like, like with Dallas,
Jackson: for example, actually, Chris, could you, are there any examples that you can remember where
Jackson: you think that law, law should Trump, uh, code law?
Jackson: Cause you said you think there are some, so there must be one that's happened or when
Tyler: you can imagine like sanctions is a good example.
Tyler: Like, you know, if somebody, if North Korea steals a bunch of money and then someone is
Tyler: forced to freeze that money on chain, so they can't like develop nuclear weapons to threaten
Tyler: innocent people.
Tyler: I don't think a lot of people are too upset about that, but it does kind of fly in the
Tyler: face of the idea of the blockchain.
Chris: I think, yeah, I think there's a piece about setting expectations here, right?
Chris: Like circles freeze function, for example, everybody knows that's there.
Chris: Uh, and like, that is like an extension of the law into the blockchain, right?
Chris: Um, where, where it sometimes gets questionable is like, you know, things like reorgs and
Chris: rollbacks, like, uh, with what something similar to what, with what arbitrary did with the
Chris: buy bit hack.
Chris: I think it was, um, I, I personally, I think that was a good move given like what arbitrary
Chris: professors to be, um, but yeah, that's a great example, Tyler, I totally agree.
Jackson: Okay.
Jackson: So I guess if like enough of the government powers agree and that like some entity is
Jackson: bad, like North Korea, then we're okay with it interfering with the freedom of code and
Jackson: the freedom of the blockchain is kind of what you're saying in the North Korea example.
Chris: Um, yeah, I just, I think like the system is what it does, right?
Chris: If the system freezes $300 million of North Korean assets, that's what the system is.
Tyler: Um, yeah, for Bitcoin, I would prefer that Bitcoin remain such a ship resistant, but
Tyler: I would never do anything to like enable a use case like that.
Tyler: That is unlawful.
Jackson: That's true.
Chris: Yeah.
Jackson: For the record, me as well.
Jackson: And our opinions are then do not reflect our employers.
Chris: Very least.
Jackson: Yeah.
Jackson: Speaking of the, the Kimmy, uh, Kimmy three, there's a lot of hype, Chris.
Jackson: Have you tried it?
Jackson: Why didn't you purple fortune with Kimmy three?
Chris: I tried to try it.
Chris: I think the only way that you can get it right now is through their website, kimmy.com, Kimmy,
Chris: something like that.
Chris: Um, and I, I swerved that, um, but from what I'm seeing on the internet, it's very good.
Tyler: And what does it tell though, what's like real and what's just hype.
Tyler: So I'll be a little bit of a bear here, but like, I think that it looks really good on
Tyler: the benchmarks, but I feel like the open weight models are known to like, look better on the
Tyler: benchmarks than they do in real life.
Tyler: Um, because the benchmarks, at least the ones that are open are like very gameable, I think.
Tyler: And they have a huge incentive to like make their models look good on the benchmarks.
Tyler: And I think that the, that perception doesn't always meet reality.
Tyler: And then the other thing I saw was that like they can reach these benchmarks, Kimmy can,
Tyler: but it uses like 10 X the tokens to achieve the task as a better model.
Tyler: So it's like the smarter model is just has more intelligence embedded in it.
Tyler: So it has to do less, um, test time compute.
Tyler: So it doesn't have to spend as many thinking tokens.
Tyler: And so like Kimmy, because of that is going to be slower and it's going to use more tokens.
Tyler: And so even if it's cheaper, if it's using more tokens, there's some crossover where
Tyler: it actually becomes more expensive.
Tyler: And so on the like, you know, per task or cost per task kind of metric that basically
Tyler: ignores the amount of reasoning tokens or like incorporates that, then I don't think
Tyler: it's quite as good as the frontier shows.
Tyler: And like, I don't know, have you guys ever used how extensively have you used the open
Tyler: models?
Tyler: Like, like Kimmy K two or 2.5 wasn't nearly this hyped, but like people were saying that
Tyler: it was as good as like sonnet back in the day when I was using sonnet a lot.
Tyler: And I would use Kimmy and it was like so much dumber and noticeably dumber, and it was really,
Tyler: really bad at using tools.
Tyler: So it would just like, I'd send it off to do something.
Tyler: And then it would just be like, ah, I don't know how to do this.
Tyler: And it like has access to the MCP or, you know, there's just like stuff that it could
Tyler: be doing and I have to product to do it.
Tyler: And that kind of soured me on open models for a while.
Chris: I mean, Jackson, you're like, what's your experience with open models?
Chris: I guess you're mostly using run local, but is it similar to Tyler or, uh, I've never
Jackson: read anything about how good people think Quinn three or GLM 4.7 are, but they're not
Jackson: great and they're the only ones my computer can handle.
Jackson: Uh, yeah, I can't even compare them to a model because I've been using such good models for
Jackson: like the last few months.
Jackson: And like my brain is like a little hamster wheel, like once it spins, it's gone.
Jackson: So all I can say is that the open models I've used are not great, like not good enough for
Jackson: me to be worth my time.
Chris: Yeah, I'm with you.
Chris: I had a minor meltdown over Claude guardrails yesterday.
Chris: Uh, nothing, nothing suspect.
Tyler: All right.
Tyler: related.
Chris: No, uh, I just, I'm a man with a lot of like eclectic, potentially on-chain interests.
Chris: Okay.
Chris: And, uh, yeah, it was just, uh, I was just like getting really annoyed, you know, getting
Chris: silently knocked down to 4.8.
Chris: And so I signed up to maple AI and they have, uh, Kimmy, I think he's at 2.6, uh, and one
Chris: of the Quinn's as well.
Chris: And yeah, I like, I gave it, I gave it a shot.
Chris: Um, but yeah, the, like the Delta is really noticeable.
Chris: You definitely lose something, uh, for, for not being constrained by the Claude guardrails.
Tyler: Yeah.
Tyler: I feel like the, um, the GPT guardrails are less annoying and also you don't have guardrails
Tyler: on Opus, which Opus is still probably much better than Kimmy.
Tyler: I think in practice, I would, I would guess, um, but yeah, you were mentioning Chris that
Tyler: you thought that like GPT is good at coding, but it's like less of a bro than Claude.
Chris: Yeah.
Tyler: Have you just become, you know, very accustomed to Claude's, Claude-isms and like you feel
Tyler: like you have a nice friend there and then you go to GPT and GPT is like this cold calculating
Tyler: like personality list AI and you're just like, can't get along with them, but you could delegate
Tyler: work to them.
Chris: Are you asking if I have developed a Jackson style parasocial relationship with Claude?
Chris: Is that the question?
Tyler: Um, not, not imply quite Jackson level because I think that's like extreme.
Tyler: Like I think that there's a little bit of like, uh, almost like quasi-romantic, but
Jackson: like, there's nothing to be ashamed on a physical level.
Jackson: Yeah.
Jackson: We all enjoy AI on our own way.
Jackson: Okay.
Tyler: Yeah.
Chris: Don't judge that.
Chris: You know?
Chris: Yeah.
Chris: I think we should all be free to enjoy AI however we want.
Chris: Um, but yeah, I, I do, I think, I think Claude is a cool guy.
Chris: Um, and I, I don't know how they've achieved that.
Chris: Like I'm not particularly an EA person and I feel like a lot of Claude's, you know, philosophy
Chris: and the methodology for training Claude is downstream of that.
Tyler: Um, but I guess I wouldn't use cool guy to describe Claude.
Tyler: I feel like a lot of like hall monitor energy.
Tyler: And then, um, I do think Claude is a better writer and has like more human kind of feeling
Tyler: to it, but I don't necessarily like vibe with the personality, but like I appreciate it
Tyler: almost more than something without personality.
Tyler: So it's like some personality is better than no personality, but I still think that Claude
Tyler: is kind of a dweeb sometimes.
Jackson: Yeah.
Chris: I stamped that.
Chris: He's an eager beaver.
Chris: Whereas codex is like the most cracked programmer you've ever met who just does exactly what
Chris: you say.
Chris: Um, yeah.
Tyler: But you want that sometimes.
Chris: Sometimes you do, but sometimes I want, I want to like riffle, I want to be like, Hey,
Chris: Claude, what do you think about this?
Chris: Like, should we do it this way?
Chris: Should we do it that way?
Chris: And then, you know, Claude will protect my feelings.
Chris: Like he won't be like, no, that's wrong.
Tyler: He'll be like, Oh, we're up five bucks boys.
Jackson: Whoa.
Jackson: Yeah.
Tyler: Oh, we had done a hundred X. Like Claude told us, we would be up a hundred dollars right
Tyler: now because we'd be 20 X the leverage from where we are now.
Tyler: So we'd be up a hundo.
Tyler: Five X leverage is this is why we can't have Claude running purple fortune.
Tyler: I hereby want to put it to vote that we like have to have some kind of like, has to be
Tyler: like either an unhinged, like Kimmy AI that, that does purple fortune, or at least a GPT
Tyler: that we think is going to do what we tell it to.
Jackson: We got to use a free, you know, local model, Chris, the dumbest, the dumbest local model
Jackson: you can, the smallest and just let it go wild, like a lot of parameters.
Jackson: Yeah, speaking about chat or like GPT versus Claude, I ran an experiment today with like
Jackson: a pretty difficult, um, problem, um, like coding problem because that's my job.
Jackson: And I was like, basically I made Fable do it and I made GPT 5.6 to it because I needed
Jackson: to talk about GPT 5.6 on the pod today.
Jackson: So they ran and the results are that Fable one-shotted it like a champ as it always does,
Jackson: but it took, I believe three times as long in terms of like a clock time.
Jackson: Yeah.
Jackson: In terms of clock time.
Tyler: Exactly.
Jackson: Yeah.
Jackson: And it costs about three times as much as well.
Jackson: Um, so all that to say that Fable is still rocking it on GPT 5.6, but.
Tyler: So GPT 5.6 didn't one shot it, it needed some more steering.
Tyler: Is that what you're saying?
Jackson: It thought it one shot at it in like 32 minutes, but it was wrong.
Tyler: And how did you discover it was wrong?
Tyler: Obviously not viewing the code.
Tyler: So you asked Fable to ask if GPT was wrong.
Jackson: Uh, I'll be honest.
Jackson: So I looked at the code a little bit and then I got Opus 4.8 doesn't be the judge.
Chris: I think the anthropic models are like excellent managers, uh, that like overbearing whole
Chris: monitor types, uh, they're willing to talk smack about codecs as well.
Chris: Like, like Ford will just be like, yeah, let me kill these silly codecs models that are
Chris: ruining my code base.
Chris: Um, yeah.
Jackson: Yeah.
Jackson: I recognize I should have gotten like five unbiased AI reviewers to review the two AIs
Jackson: code.
Jackson: Yeah.
Tyler: Did you have a GPT review the Fable code?
Tyler: No, you only had Opus.
Tyler: This is like, uh, it isn't a jury of peers here that you're constructing.
Tyler: This is a biased, you know, jury.
Jackson: That's true.
Jackson: Yeah.
Tyler: I should have done.
Jackson: I object to this test.
Jackson: You object to this test.
Jackson: Well, the census from what people say is the 5.6 is fast.
Jackson: It's punchy, but like, you kind of have to tell it what to do.
Jackson: And I'm at the point with AI where like, I just tell like five tables what to do.
Jackson: And then I like zone out for awhile.
Jackson: And then I come back and they've done everything I want.
Jackson: And maybe I'm a little bit too lazy and I, uh, I do a mix of that and like distributing
Jackson: jobs from Babel to sonnets.
Jackson: Um, and that's kind of where I think a chat GPT 5.6 comes in.
Jackson: And I think that's what Chris, you say you use it for is for actual task execution for
Jackson: the speed.
Jackson: Is that right?
Chris: Yeah, exactly.
Chris: Like if the task is quite well scoped and I just need it to be done correctly, like
Chris: letter correctly, I think 5.6 is good for that.
Jackson: But it's not a gig of brain.
Jackson: I'm going to figure out all the ambiguities that you didn't lay out to me directly.
Chris: Totally.
Chris: And like, even like the pull request descriptions are like, they're so terse it like assumes
Chris: so much knowledge.
Chris: I'm like, dude, I don't like lay it out for me a little bit.
Chris: Like I, I didn't read this.
Chris: Like I asked you to do it.
Chris: So like, you know, I need you to do my job and explain to me what the job was.
Jackson: Um, yeah, I'll get, I'll bring you back on the next spot though.
Jackson: And if, if Opus 4.8 misrepresented the competition, I'll let you guys know.
Jackson: But for now, okay, we trust.
Jackson: And then kind of similar conversation, the cost, you know, I think people talk about
Jackson: are these companies profitable?
Jackson: How are they going to make money?
Jackson: And I'm kind of starting to see my costs rise.
Jackson: What about you guys?
Tyler: I mean, Fable is so expensive.
Tyler: Like I think that my costs went way up when I started using it.
Tyler: That being said, it is probably worth it because it does noticeably better work than Opus.
Tyler: It's nice that I don't pay for it myself that my employer pays for it all.
Tyler: And that is reflected in my increased productivity.
Chris: So I mean, they were supposed to take Fable off the $200 max plan, I'm pretty sure five
Chris: days ago, and they keep extending it for five days, obviously, because they need to compete
Chris: with other models.
Chris: So I think the current five day extension might end in two days.
Chris: That's, that's what I think.
Jackson: So for any person out there, yeah, they need to make up for the government, rugging the
Jackson: crap out of us, you know, like we miss some days from the original deadline, right?
Chris: That's so true.
Jackson: That's so true.
Tyler: I think they're mostly just caught in a competitive dynamic against open AI, where like open AI
Tyler: is going a little bit harder on the usage.
Tyler: And so they like need to kind of keep up.
Tyler: And the rumor is that they were going to launch a new Opus, I think, soon and then use that
Tyler: to wean people off of Fable within the plan.
Tyler: Do you have a personal like clog or GPT subscription?
Tyler: I guess Chris, you have a Maple subscription now.
Chris: Yeah, I I'm out of control, dude.
Chris: It's like, I think I spend more on AI than food at this point.
Chris: Yeah, I've clawed and now Maple.
Chris: That's it.
Tyler: I used to have a 200 clawed.
Chris: Yeah, I have a 200 clawed.
Chris: I'm out of control, dude.
Chris: I'm like, do you max it out?
Tyler: Do you get like limited from your usage?
Chris: I try to max it out of principle, you know, like just to use as much.
Chris: Water as possible, but sometimes I fall short.
Jackson: You know, the water thing is crazy.
Jackson: I hope we haven't talked about on the podcast, but quick side note, I like go home to Georgia
Jackson: and I'm like telling my family who live in the suburbs of Atlanta, man, I so awesome.
Jackson: It's like way smarter than me.
Jackson: I'm useless now.
Jackson: And then they're like, but what about the water?
Jackson: And I'm like, what about the water?
Tyler: Are they like, do you want to go golfing this weekend, by the way, and like eat some almonds?
Jackson: Yeah, dude, the targeted like hate news or whatever is so weird in the world.
Chris: I mean, do we even want to touch on the evaporative cooling?
Chris: Like reason for that, I guess rumor or like piece of news or like, we just let our listeners
Chris: like let them be confused.
Jackson: If anyone can concisely state why the water concern is not legit, that would be fire.
Chris: Okay.
Chris: It seems like I volunteered myself.
Chris: My understanding is that some early versions, I want to like drain Lake Michigan.
Chris: That's what it is.
Chris: Tyler called it the astralification of the US.
Chris: Yeah.
Chris: That's his goal.
Chris: No, no, no.
Chris: I think like my understanding is early versions of these data centers that get slapped together
Chris: really quickly, like obviously, you know, they need electricity and they need to get
Chris: rid of waste heat, right?
Chris: Like that's a big problem in computing.
Chris: And so early versions use evaporative cooling, which obviously, you know, you put the water
Chris: somewhere, it gets hot, it evaporates and gets rid of the heat.
Chris: Um, it seems like, you know, more and more sophisticated versions of these data centers
Chris: are doing what they've done for a long time, which is closed loop systems where, you know,
Chris: the water gets hot and then gets cooled and then in a loop and, uh, yeah, therefore users
Chris: substantially less water.
Chris: So that's my understanding of how, how that came to be.
Jackson: And then back to the AI cost thing, uh, cause I had some interesting numbers that I noticed.
Jackson: It kind of seems like the way they're making money to me is they're making better models
Jackson: that are like undeniably better.
Jackson: So then you use them and they could just cost more.
Jackson: They both like use more tokens because the context windows are better and, um, they have
Jackson: like a higher charge rate.
Jackson: And then like for me personally, they've also gotten a lot more addicting.
Jackson: Like I find that I'm, I'm using them a lot more, but that's kind of a more personal thing.
Jackson: I think the, the real cost increases like them releasing new models.
Jackson: You go into the new models.
Jackson: I think that net increases your spend if you're spending the same amount of time working.
Jackson: I don't know.
Jackson: What do you guys think?
Jackson: Have you looked into your cost trends as you've gone from like sonnet opus cable?
Tyler: It's hard to like untangle.
Tyler: Yeah.
Tyler: Like why am I using it more because the models are much better or because I've just been
Tyler: using AI now for like six months and the depth of my power user, like all this stuff that
Tyler: I shoved through it now is just so extreme.
Tyler: And I feel like it's probably a little bit of both.
Tyler: Like you give it more because it's so useful, but also like more and more of these tasks
Tyler: and the, like the work scope of what I give it has just increased a bunch as well.
Tyler: And now that's just like stuff that's built into my day.
Tyler: But yeah, it's kind of like, I, you hear about some other companies and they're like, like
Tyler: I think like Uber, there was a thing about how they limit, I think employees to like
Tyler: $200 of tokens a week.
Tyler: I do not know what I would do if I was limited to 200 tokens a week.
Chris: What are they doing?
Chris: Are they really slack with their eyes?
Chris: Like what are they doing?
Tyler: Yeah.
Tyler: Are they like a git push with a sonnet?
Jackson: That's so gross.
Chris: Like their fingies?
Chris: Like, yeah, what's going on?
Jackson: I'm not going to say numbers, but yeah, I'm not under the 200 a week personally.
Jackson: I think I could get back to it.
Tyler: I don't even know.
Tyler: How would you ration yourself if you had to go from current to 200 a week?
Tyler: Like would you use shittier models?
Tyler: Would you do less work?
Tyler: Would you just do stuff more by hand or is there a whole like types of tasks that you
Tyler: wouldn't have it do?
Jackson: That's kind of all of it.
Jackson: I mean, I know exactly what I would do is I would take it back to sonnet, which was good
Jackson: enough at executing tasks that I define well.
Jackson: And then I would do all the thinking work that I've off boarded to fable since then.
Tyler: So you do you'd think for yourself again.
Jackson: Yeah.
Jackson: I'm going to become an empty blob and an empty shell.
Jackson: My fable is my only representation shortly.
Jackson: Please don't release a better bottle.
Chris: I joke that I'm just like a context window extender for fable.
Chris: Like he puts stuff in here and then I like get it back to him when he needs it, you know,
Chris: like a rag database.
Jackson: Empirically, definitely producing more able to produce a lot more and able to parallelize
Jackson: across multiple tasks a lot better overlay GitHub contributions from 2026 and note when
Jackson: I switched Opus and Babel and it becomes dark green.
Jackson: This is not a flex.
Jackson: It is only to show that like, yes, we're spending more or I'm spending more, but also I'm producing
Jackson: more.
Jackson: So, you know, it is it is working.
Tyler: Yeah, there's no sorry to commits cleanly like translate to, you know, quality and like
Tyler: impact.
Jackson: Yes.
Jackson: In the in my case, because I'm not doing like commits for the sake of commits, I'm doing
Jackson: I mean, you can trust me just like you could trust me on all things.
Chris: What are you saying about my commits, dude?
Jackson: What are you saying?
Chris: Do you have something to say?
Chris: Yeah, I didn't even look at your stats.
Chris: There's no way.
Chris: There's no way I could have produced from a product perspective what I produced in the
Chris: last year and a half without a there's no chance no shot, so.
Tyler: It is really hard to generate a lot of slop by hand.
Chris: Well, I also I was quite good at that as well.
Chris: So you probably have a much Yeah, that was an excellent joke.
Jackson: And it hit home pretty hard.
Jackson: I was like, Oh, that's exactly what I am.
Tyler: Do you think in the future you're going to have to like exercise your mind in the way
Tyler: that you like go to the gym and lift weights because you're like, Oh, my, my thinking faculties
Tyler: are going to atrophy if I don't like occasionally do some stuff to think for myself.
Tyler: I do feel like some of my skills are getting like fuzzier, like the thought of like writing
Tyler: a big long document on my own with no help is like terrifying because like that sounds
Tyler: so boring and I would just like sit there and struggle to think of how I want to phrase
Tyler: something or like what's the right word for this moment and it's just like tedious but
Tyler: yeah, I probably used to be better at that and now it'd be tough.
Jackson: I hear you.
Jackson: Yeah, Chris.
Jackson: Can you write a compiling like Kotlin state machine right now at this moment Kotlin.
Chris: I don't think I can assign a Kotlin variable right now if that's what you're asking.
Chris: Some other language like Rust or Golang.
Chris: Yeah, I probably I make it work it take me a couple of tries that I'm definitely like
Chris: out of whack.
Jackson: Yeah, I was just like, you know, I was pretty good at the coding interviews that like writing
Jackson: syntactically correct fast code, but like it I haven't done it in so long and I know
Jackson: for sure I couldn't do Kotlin.
Jackson: I don't I just mentioned this language totally randomly, by the way, I don't think I can
Jackson: I could do it, which is yeah, exactly what you're saying, Tyler, like I would have been
Jackson: able to do it, but I don't need to anymore.
Jackson: Like let's say Python, I could write Python and it's like writing English.
Jackson: So it's still really easy to remember and like writing a doc writing a doc is so like
Jackson: two years ago, man, you just tell the tell the AI, don't tell anybody we're working
Jackson: on.
Tyler: Yeah, proliferation of like work slop is definitely a problem.
Tyler: And I think I've been guilty of this to some extent.
Tyler: I feel like the pressures that you're put on and in these workplaces where everyone
Tyler: is adopting AI, it's just like, you're expected to do more and like cover more surface area
Tyler: because you can like automate a lot of stuff and you can use AI to like scale yourself
Tyler: in terms of like monitoring slack and monitoring all this multiple projects.
Tyler: But then you kind of need to like, if you get something coming in, you need to like
Tyler: turn it and get it out like as soon as you can just move on to the next thing.
Tyler: And that lends itself to just like delegating to AI, hopefully doing like a quick once over
Tyler: read, making sure it hits your quality bar, and then like putting it out there.
Tyler: And then probably your coworker is like, Tyler, just send me this doc, Claude, can you go
Tyler: read it and summarize it for me?
Tyler: So it's like, just this, the doc is like this, like in intermediate artifact that just helps
Tyler: the AIs interface with each other.
Tyler: But yeah, like the proliferation of work slop, I like yearn for going back to the artisanal
Tyler: time where I could like spend time and write something and put it in my own voice.
Tyler: And it didn't have all the tells of being AI generated.
Tyler: And I was like, very proud of it, but it's like, who has time to grind at that level
Tyler: these days?
Chris: I think the reward functions are probably broken in like a lot of places right now where
Chris: like, you know, it's like, who cares how we get up the mountain, like the mountains there,
Chris: we're seeing other people get up the mountain, we just got to scramble.
Chris: But I think in the limit, it like maybe a little bit of the handcrafted artisanal nature
Chris: of work returns, right?
Chris: When I think like, you know, the quality bar is starting to drop at some like apps I use
Chris: on the day to day.
Chris: And I'm noticing more subtle bugs.
Chris: And I think, yeah, I think like, I think strategy and like, being deliberate comes back slowly.
Chris: But I think we have to go through this hill climb of scrambling up fable to get there.
Tyler: We have to go through the great winter of slop before we can emerge into a beautiful
Tyler: spring of artisanal docs and handwritten Kotlin code.
Chris: Yeah, we just have to tread water, you just have to keep our head above the slop.
Tyler: I believe, yeah.
Jackson: Those days are over boys.
Jackson: Yeah, back on like the exercising your mind thing, like, I think we'll like see a decline
Jackson: in our minds.
Jackson: I'll need some studies to show me why I need my mind to be sharp before I am compelled
Jackson: to sharpen it up, I think.
Tyler: Do you read studies that are like, you need to have big muscles, and then you're like,
Tyler: that's the reason you go to the gym and lift weights, Jackson?
Tyler: Or do you do it because you're like, tight, I have big muscles, I like the way this feels,
Tyler: and I like that I can like lift stuff in a non taxing way.
Tyler: Like having a smart mind, I think, feels good.
Tyler: Yeah, I'm just kind of extrapolating.
Tyler: I imagine it feels good to have a smart mind.
Tyler: I can't speak from experience, but.
Jackson: And you guys are so humble and upfront about your intelligence.
Jackson: I don't think I've commented on my own at all, but this feeling, well, hey, I never
Chris: said I was smart.
Chris: I would never say that.
Chris: Yeah, you can keep the humble train going for the AI training.
Jackson: I don't know, I guess like, I think if I have intellectual hobbies, like I'm working on
Jackson: my Spanish and my Korean, like then I'll do it.
Jackson: But I don't think if it's like for the sake of having a sharp mind, like I'm like, I used
Jackson: to be really good at mental math.
Jackson: And after like, how many years, six years out of college, I can't multiply like three
Jackson: digit numbers anymore in my head.
Jackson: And sometimes I'm like, should I do it just for the sake of being like a calculator?
Jackson: And the answer is no, because it doesn't give me anything.
Tyler: So Spanish and like Korean too, I mean, I guess in some abstract sense, maybe it was
Tyler: good at some time to be good at like mentally, um, multiplying numbers together.
Chris: That rules though.
Chris: Can we say, can we say that rules?
Chris: I think that rules.
Chris: I've never done that.
Chris: Have you done that Tyler?
Tyler: No, no, not at that level.
Tyler: Although I did, I did some job interviews coming out of college for like options trading
Tyler: and they, they like would put me in a room and like ask me shit like that.
Tyler: And I like felt, or they'd ask me like these like random brain teasers and I'd just be
Tyler: like, bro, what?
Jackson: Like, I'm not going to think about this interviews and that's what they are.
Jackson: Like first they're testing your mental math and then they were testing statistics.
Jackson: And unfortunately I did not miss statistics.
Jackson: I was kind of bad, but the mental math is fine.
Chris: Yeah.
Chris: Yeah, I spent probably 200 hours on lead codes, like quite, like quite consecutive and, and
Tyler: how many monsters were consumed per hour of lead code.
Tyler: There's like a 200 can monster, like, um, like chair that's been duct taped together
Tyler: just out of the frame.
Jackson: I don't believe that monster is the strongest, the strongest thing you were taking for that.
Jackson: That's all I'm going to say.
Chris: Whoa, accusations.
Chris: Um, no, it was just, it was just, uh, a throne of white monster.
Chris: Um, but to your point, Jackson, like with the mental math, I, I feel like lead codes,
Chris: uh, sits in like a similar for me personally, like niche where I'm like, it's something
Chris: I had to do for job interviews and like to get better at my craft.
Chris: But in hindsight, I think like the type of like insane grinding on like just trying to
Chris: find the patterns in this list of like a hundred problems that you might get is like maybe
Chris: not actually the best use of like your time, uh, in terms of like, you know, if you want
Chris: to like build something interested in complicated, like interesting and complicated, like maybe
Chris: you're better off like doing a lecture series on game theory or something.
Jackson: We could gangster right here, but kind of like what I think you're saying and what I
Jackson: think I was saying is in response to Tyler's question about exercise in your mind, it sounds
Jackson: like these AI's free up our mind to focus on the things we actually want to do.
Jackson: Like no one wants to do leak code, but they might want to build something interesting
Jackson: for Chris or they might want to speak to Spanish native people, you know?
Jackson: Yeah, and George, there's a lot of a lot of Spanish people in charge.
Jackson: So that's, that's our response.
Jackson: Yeah.
Tyler: Tyler, the way that I feel the atrophy happening most acutely, I feel is like, um, thinking
Tyler: really quickly on my feet and then like verbalizing and like maybe having like debates and stuff
Tyler: like that.
Tyler: Like, I feel like in some meetings or circumstances where I'm talking to someone all, yeah, just
Tyler: be a little bit slower than I would like.
Tyler: And then afterwards I'll be like, oh, if I had just like connected that dot in the moment,
Tyler: I would have like had that point.
Tyler: Um, and that's probably also a function of, uh, working remotely and not having like quite
Tyler: as many built-in social interactions in my life as I used to.
Tyler: So maybe that's just as much of the atrophy there as it is from like me talking to AI
Tyler: all day.
Tyler: Like if we, yeah, if I was in an office or if I was working for a company that required
Tyler: me to be in the office, would I actually be talking to people all day or would I still
Tyler: just be talking to an AI and just like swap rambling into the terminal, into the whisper
Jackson: terminal window as well.
Jackson: Here's what you do.
Jackson: We can, we can get your quippiness back.
Jackson: You turn on fable to do your work and then you go and you get your baby and you put on
Jackson: voice to text, um, like conversation AI on grok, put on a lady's voice, put your baby
Jackson: in front of the camera and just like chat with chat with her.
Tyler: No, I think this podcast is my, uh, this is my lead code.
Tyler: This is sharpening my mind and the, and yeah, oh, they, they let you do that, uh, of, of
Tyler: smart people, whether it be Chris or whether it be swag dog, you guys are my, my sharpeners,
Chris: they let you talk to people, man.
Chris: They just put me in a room with a computer and they say, invert a binary tree.
Jackson: Like that's been my career up until this point did crazy.
Jackson: I think the podcast is evidence per all of your super famous shorts, Tyler, that you're
Jackson: still as sharp as ever.
Jackson: If you're any sharper, you'd be breaking YouTube's algorithm.
Jackson: Yeah.
Chris: I'm a little worried.
Tyler: Oh, we're about to break 10.
Jackson: Jeez.
Jackson: It just popped from six.
Jackson: It was six, like two minutes ago.
Chris: This time you need to, you need to do the next one.
Tyler: I think that Jared just got wrecked on chain again.
Tyler: And then we're getting a dividend from Cheeto, you know, something's happening on Solana.
Chris: For sure.
Chris: Hold on.
Jackson: You're calling it Cheeto, but it's a J. What's going on?
Jackson: Is that what it's called?
Chris: The ticker is JTO, but the token is Cheeto.
Chris: So Cheeto, I think controls Solana staking.
Chris: And the way that Solana transactions are broadcasted is at an epoch, which I think is every two
Chris: days, they decide which validator is going to get to construct which block.
Chris: So you know, ahead of time.
Chris: And Cheeto, so, you know, like each individual validator can like order the transactions
Chris: in whatever way they want.
Chris: And Cheeto, I think is, has an agreement on how to order the transactions and funnel it
Chris: to one meb bot.
Chris: There's one meb bot.
Chris: So I don't have an opinion about that.
Chris: But yeah.
Chris: Yeah.
Jackson: It's, I guess it's like a monopoly, right?
Jackson: I guess on the, on the chain.
Chris: Some would say.
Chris: Some would say that's a monopoly.
Jackson: Yes.
Jackson: But maybe it's for the best.
Jackson: Cause it's giving back to the people.
Jackson: Just sounds like a government tax, basically, I'm there.
Chris: Yeah.
Chris: It's giving some back.
Jackson: We can say that.
Jackson: Oh, okay.
Jackson: How much do you, what's the split?
Tyler: 10.
Tyler: Now it's back down higher bar than I do.
Tyler: One, I guess I just thought of this.
Tyler: Why is there even MEV on Solana, like if the, the, I guess the concern about MEV is that
Tyler: it causes like an incentive to reorg, right?
Tyler: But then if they decide who makes the blocks two days in advance and it's like slotted
Tyler: in, then are there no like reorgs because somebody just like, you know, proposes a block
Tyler: on their slot and then they move on.
Tyler: And so why does there need to be this GTO entity?
Chris: Well the answer is bribes knowing who is going to be able to order the transaction two days
Chris: in advance means you know who to bribe, right?
Chris: So my understanding is, and I'm not big across Solana MEV because you know, I don't have
Chris: connections in that world.
Chris: My understanding is GTO works in that space somehow.
Chris: The specifics allude me.
Tyler: Yeah, I have no idea.
Jackson: It was just something that seemed to me.
Jackson: Is GTO kind of like an end game for like movable chains or is there like an end game where
Jackson: like one company or one entity ends up being the MEV?
Jackson: Like that's kind of what Jared is now, right?
Tyler: And then they have this thing called Flashbots that I think it's a way for people like Jared
Tyler: to submit MEV opportunities to this like pool and then validators who participate in the
Tyler: pool can then, you know, take those MEV bundles and incorporate them in the blocks.
Tyler: And so everyone is kind of pulling from the same MEV pool and then that means that no validators
Tyler: inherently like better at MEV than any other, right?
Tyler: And so I guess GTO is just doing the same for Solana.
Tyler: Maybe that answers my own question earlier is like the reason GTO exists is because even
Tyler: though the block slots are predetermined if any one Solana block producer got like really
Tyler: good at extracting MEV better than the other ones, then they would get more systematically
Tyler: more revenue and then potentially like a greater share of the network and more validators and
Tyler: then they would be producing more blocks, but that probably wouldn't happen on Solana
Tyler: anyways because they could just like decide to like, oh, you're like becoming too powerful.
Tyler: Okay, well, like, you know, we'll break you up a little bit to preserve the illusion of
Chris: being more distributed, right, and those are your words, not mine.
Chris: But AI.
Chris: I will say one of the utilities here of the Ethereum approach and I don't think it's perfect,
Chris: it might not even be good, but is there's like a free market for MEV, right?
Chris: So you can kind of like, the people have to compete or the MEV extractors have to compete
Chris: against each other for this, which necessarily, you know, drives their cut down.
Chris: It gives more to the validators as they're paying more and more gas to get in the top
Chris: of the block.
Chris: Whether that happens with Jito, I don't know.
Jackson: Okay, cool.
Jackson: Well, I think that's a good place to end the pod, we're at a good time.
Jackson: I'm sorry that we keep baiting all of our listeners on the agent at commerce, but all
Jackson: this crazy, awesome stuff is happening and we'd rather talk about it.
Tyler: Is that like a signal that none of us are actually excited about agentic commerce, we're
Tyler: all agentic commerce bearers?
Jackson: I really want to talk about it personally, but as we said evergreen topics, we save them
Jackson: until we need them.
Chris: I want to talk about it too, but for like bad reasons, like really terrible reasons,
Chris: like maybe we shouldn't talk about it, I don't know.
Jackson: That's exactly why we should talk about it.
Tyler: Because you're a bear and you're going to like, you know, make everyone a bear on agentic
Tyler: commerce or because what are the bad reasons?
Chris: I don't spoil it, I don't spoil it, there are specific reasons, they're very specific.
Tyler: Okay, tune in next time to figure out why Chris has a extreme grudge against the agentic
Tyler: commerce.
Tyler: He's plotting against the whole concept this whole intervening week.
Jackson: All right, and we peace out at $10 up.
Jackson: Very well, guests, everyone throw a wave.
Tyler: Thank you, Gito.
Chris: All right.
Insert: Thank you, Gito, for sponsoring.